<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prabhat Pokharel</title>
    <description>This is my blog</description>
    <link>http://pokharelprabhat.com.np/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://pokharelprabhat.com.np/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Phishing email</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Phishing emails are composed in such a way that the information in the email attracts a recipient to click on a malicious link or download a malicious content. Most of the times these emails are random and we don’t care much about. However, at times we have attackers targeting a victim with sufficient research on the subject matter the possible victim might be interested in. Say, if you are traveling to some place, you might be sent a phishing email with offers on hotels for your stay. These types of phishing emails are known as spear-phishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Prabhat_ep_1.png&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general there are few things that can keep you safe from phising email attacks. Some of these are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Always remember that the email address of the sender could be fake and can’t be trusted.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Links may be spoofed, so copy the link and paste on the  browser’s address bar to check if it is genuine.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Attachments should only be clicked or downloaded if its something you are expecting from someone you already know or trust.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Check for spellings and grammars. Any mistake as such is always suspicious.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Unclear salutations or salutations without your name should not be trusted.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Check the signatures, most of the times phishing emails do not have genuine signatures but this is not always the case. Sometimes fake signatures might seem legitimate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If possible check the source. This could the best thing to be done for final confirmation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Prabhat_ep_2.png&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; width=&quot;270&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compare the &lt;strong&gt;Received: from&lt;/strong&gt; address with the &lt;strong&gt;mailfrom=&lt;/strong&gt; address (shown by red arrow heads).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check the links in the message body (shown by green arrow heads).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Prabhat_ep_3.png&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. The images are from a test phishing email written only for the purpose of general awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 10:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://pokharelprabhat.com.np/blog/security/2016/01/23/Phishing-email/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pokharelprabhat.com.np/blog/security/2016/01/23/Phishing-email/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Preventing Facebook account hack</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Facebook account hacking is on the rise, being the most most popular social networking site, this is a threat to millions of users across the globe who have a lot of personal and private information stored in their accounts. It is difficult to train general users with sophisticated techniques. However, it is important that the users follow simple guidelines and remain aware of the immense risk we are exposed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, we will go through two really effective features Facebook has provided that can help you keep your account safe.&lt;br /&gt;
The first one is &lt;strong&gt;Login Notifications&lt;/strong&gt;. You can configure your account to get notified for any login attempt being made from a device that you have never used to access (login to) your account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/13.png&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is simple and easy to use feature. Just choose the notification method you prefer and you are all set to go. Go to &lt;strong&gt;Settings&lt;/strong&gt;, then to &lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt; tab and then edit the &lt;strong&gt;Login Notifications&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/1.png&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second one is &lt;strong&gt;Login Approval&lt;/strong&gt;. You can configure your account to use a secret code before you use a new browser. This is something like using a pin number while using your payment card (ATM/debit/credit card). So, even if someone cracks down your password, this user can not login to your account until he/she knows your security code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2.png&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, as in case of &lt;strong&gt;Login Notifications&lt;/strong&gt;, go to &lt;strong&gt;Settings&lt;/strong&gt;, then to &lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt; tab and then edit the &lt;strong&gt;Login Approvals&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/3.png&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;  
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/4.png&quot; height=&quot;120&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/5.png&quot; height=&quot;130&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will receive a text message containing a six digit security on your phone number. Please remember this will be sent to the number that is linked to your Facebook account. You will always have the option of changing the phone number, if you need to. Once you submit the security code, you will get a confirmation that the code is working fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/6.png&quot; height=&quot;130&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you try editing the &lt;strong&gt;Login Approvals&lt;/strong&gt; after finally submitting the form, the &lt;strong&gt;Login Approvals&lt;/strong&gt; to require security code would be checked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have done all of this, you can test to check if the feature does work and is really useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use a new browser from the same device (desktop/laptop/tablet/mobile) or from a different device to login to your Facebook account. As soon as you submit the username password, you will be promoted to a form to submit the security code you had received from Facebook. If you enter the code correctly, you will be redirected to your home page, else not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/7.png&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other end, if you check the Facebook home page on the existing session through which you configured the &lt;strong&gt;Login Approvals&lt;/strong&gt;, you should receive a notification that someone has attempted to access your account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/8.png&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/9.png&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/10.png&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are also given an option to review the recent login with the geographical position from where the login was attempted. You can always reject the new login by selecting &lt;strong&gt;This wasn’t me..&lt;/strong&gt; and thus creating a new password for you Facebook account. However, in this case it is you who is making the login attempt, you can go with the second option &lt;strong&gt;This was me..&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/11.png&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you are given the option if you would want to save the new browser for the next login.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://pokharelprabhat.com.np/blog/security/2015/12/25/Preventing-Facebook-account-hack/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pokharelprabhat.com.np/blog/security/2015/12/25/Preventing-Facebook-account-hack/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Geo political aspect of information security</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Any kind of IT operation could have some kind of potential threat. We can’t assume a source of information that is free of risks towards such threats. This kind of risk rises enormously in case of outsourcing or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;offshoring. If we look into the data more then 60% of breach of actions were caused after the involvement of a third party. In case of outsourcing, if the third party organization is not directly liable for safety and security of the assets of the organization or its customers, then there is a much greater possibility of rise in the threats that the organization posses. Is there any way this can be guaranteed? This is the biggest question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since, the liability could be the major point of failure in case of risk associated with the outsourcing threat, it is important that the correct policies and regulations should be applied to make the outsourced organization liable for any breach of security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many ways we can manage risk, but the most important one in case of outsourcing or offshoring is risk transference. Risk transference can be done by following an appropriate information security governance and transfer of associated liability. This means If an organization A assigns a certain part of it task say X to organization B, then the risk associated with task X should be directly transferred to organization B. A real time example could be transfer of risk to the payment service provider by using the industry standard regulation such as PCI DSS. By doing so the merchant could make the payment service provider liable for the information at its disposal. Besides PCI DSS, there are many other standard frameworks like ISO 2700 series, SOX, HIPPA etc. These could be either state standard or industry standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said that, organization should also enforce appropriate security policy, sign an NDA and perform security audit against the third party so as to secure the assets or the transactions associated with the business functionalities. This causes the policy to be enforced not only to the direct employees but also to inside-out employees (meaning the employees outside the organization who can access the company’s data).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being a potential cyber security threat, outsourcing or offshoring have been really important aspects in the IT industry by helping organizations use their fields of expertise and thus increasing the industry efficiency, resulting in the financial benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion? 
We can’t live without outsourcing - that is a fact. So, what is it that goes wrong here? Outsourcing is not itself a threat to security, but a bad outsourcing decision is in most of the cases. One fundamental stuff that organizations should consider is to put security as an important aspect during the procurement process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://pokharelprabhat.com.np/2015/12/22/Geo-political-aspect-of-information-security/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pokharelprabhat.com.np/2015/12/22/Geo-political-aspect-of-information-security/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Financial information security overview</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We have been hearing of increase in banking fraud cases in recent years. With the increase in use of information technology and banking cards in financial sector, the nature of fraud has been shifting from traditional robbing and breaking cases to more sophisticated ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few cases in recent years…
A 17-year-old studying in class 12 sent email messages to Nabil bank’s e-banking customers asking them to change their security codes and providing links to do so. Whoever clicked on the link was redirected to a fake e-banking website. As the account holders entered their security codes they revealed their credentials. Using these details the fraudsters obtained clients money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several customers of Nepal Investment Bank Limited got emails stating that their e-banking accounts had been disabled and telling them to go to a given link to enable them to ask for a new identity and password. As its customers clicked on the link, they were informed about enabling of the account. Latter it was discovered that Rs 1.2 million of an active depositor of NIBL was stolen as one who sent the email got access to the password of the bank’s client. After the client complained about the loss of money, the bank inquired and found that money had been transferred to the accounts of three other clients of NIBL bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A racket involving three Indian nationals were arrested from Mahendranagar for withdrawing cash illegally from ATMs using fake debit cards. The biggest question was how the fraudsters got access to the clients’ pin codes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A junior staff from Himalayan Bank Limited was arrested by police for misappropriating balances. The employee used to transfer certain amounts from unclaimed accounts to the accounts of his friends and relatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do we stand?
The very first question that comes to our minds is  - “How is it possible that my card gets duplicated or its identity gets stolen?” The answer is - its very much possible and possible through:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electronic attack on a system or network at a business where cardholder data is processed, stored or transmitted. 
Physical theft of documents or devices containing cardholder data such as cardholder receipts, files, computers  and POS terminals. 
Skimming of magnetic strip data from a merchant’s POS. 
These three threats originate from the industries processing the card and cardholder data. But, there are threats which originate directly from the financial institutions. And, we already have evidences like pin codes theft and unauthorized fraudulent deposits to realize this.
At times, its the clients’ behaviour that is vulnerable to be exploited such as trusting a phishing email, inappropriate use of account and payment cards details on the internet, careless placement of card and account credentials etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, what needs to be done? 
Awareness
Information security is mostly about awareness. Awareness could be for a client, a merchant or a financial institution. The IT security policy handles the in house training and awareness inside an origanization. However, these are not intended towards the customers. This causes the end users to be a point of failure. Hence, it is extremely important that the end users get educated on privacy laws and information security awareness in order to prevent the potential risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Law and Regulation
Proper laws on information regulation and regulatory compliance requirements are to be enforcement by the state. This should include all the industries involved in electronic transaction of financial data. Proper enforcement of standard requirements such as the NRB IT Guidelines can ensure that the IT policies, procedures, controls and life-cycles are intact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proper implementation of technology
It is not a good idea to keep embracing the old ways of doing things, especially when they turn too vulnerable to be exploited. Like the use of magnetic stripe instead of chip-based cards and the pin codes instead of chip-and-pin authentication system. Its already the time we look for better approaches of doing things. These could be stuffs like: 
Tools for forensic analysis, data analytics, anomaly detection
Intrusion detection and protection system 
Vulnerability scanning 
Firewalls, crypto-system and authentication systems 
Surveillance devices
At the same time its extremely important that we identify the right choice of technology and use it properly, because even the best of the tools can’t alone guarantee that everything is safe. 
Risk assessment 
It is essential for the industries to understand that data breach can make it tough for them to retain the customers. A broken trust is almost impossible to regain. There are examples of Sony PSN and eBay hack which caused these organizations to loose a lot of customers. So, its the responsibility of the CISO to articulate the potential financial loss to the CIO/CFO. And, it is a fact that the cost in improving the security policies and infrastructure inside an organization will always be lower than the loss caused by the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information security as part of the business
Although, implementation of information security guidelines is driven by regulation, if approached in a proper way it can be used to:
Develop the ability to handle information security incidents and enforce mitigation measures.&lt;br /&gt;
Strengthen information security controls.
Protect IT assets and infrastructure. 
Increase professional skills and general awareness in IT security.
Its high time getting prepared for the challenges at our doorsteps, we already have some  tough days ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://pokharelprabhat.com.np/blog/security/2015/12/16/Financial-information-security-overview/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pokharelprabhat.com.np/blog/security/2015/12/16/Financial-information-security-overview/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Security through obscurity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Security through obscurity - meaning that you assume that no one is going to figure out flaws in your system, it is just a matter of time that you could be targeted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping your door key under the welcome mat, or keeping your passwords under your desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had the telnet port opened on some random port number, this should keep my server safe? This assumption can go wrong completely. One can easily identify the service using fingerprinting  techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what are we talking here? Anything that is hidden to be disclosed is the approach to implement security through obscurity. Suppose I am using secure shell for various administrative operations. What would be the fundamental thing to do so that the access is secured. Obviously, I can achieve 100% security by not using it at all, but that is not possible. So, on practical grounds I would use key or public key based authentication. Similarly I could have things like enforcing strong passphrase, disabling all users unless otherwise specified, disable remote connections etc. So, I could implement these and many other practices to strengthen the security involved in secure shell access. However, in contrast to that if I prefer not to carry all of those steps and just change the SSH port from 22 to say port 2345, thinking that I would be able to hide the service, and thus protect it, I would be trying to implement security through obscurity. Thus, be an idiot.  Because, it wouldn’t take more then few minutes to identify the obscured port specially when the service is exposed on a public network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standard security approach thus suggests one to follow the standards and well accepted practices to enhance security and not to hide the loop holes that you might have. However, if we think in a different most of our security practices rely on obscurity. Use of passwords, pass-phrases or high bit encryption keys are all ways of obscuring security in a different way. All of our adapted security practices implement security through obscurity in one way or the other. The only important part being the ability to determine the exact breakeven point. Failing to identify the exact point would either increase the security risk or decrease the usability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://pokharelprabhat.com.np/blog/security/2015/12/14/Security-through-obscurity/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pokharelprabhat.com.np/blog/security/2015/12/14/Security-through-obscurity/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
